(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
わため将軍のテーマ
Watame Shogun's Theme
作曲・作詞：角巻吟遊詩人団
Comp./Lyrics: Tsunomaki Troubadour Group
北風にあおられて
Blown by the north wind
流す涙を隠しつつ
While hiding the tears I shed
明日に駆け出した
I dashed towards tomorrow
わため将軍
Watame Shogun
東に泣く人のいると聞きゃ
When I hear there's someone crying in the east
毛皮でこさえたハンカチを
I'll bring a handkerchief made of fur
西に飢えた人がいりゃ
When there's a hungry person in the west
我が身すらも惜しくない
I wouldn't even begrudge my own body
人の世はげに悲しきものと
The world of humans is truly a sad thing
羊のわためじゃ味気なし
For a sheep like Watame, it's joyless
されど余剰の笑顔奪うは
But for those who steal excess smiles
悪畜生の罪悪感
A beast-like sense of guilt
退治してくれよう わため将軍
Watame Shogun will exterminate them!
走れ負いの悔やみ どんどどどどど
Run through the regrets of debt, don-dodododo
歌え浅き夢見じ めめめ
Sing through shallow dreams, me-me-me
愛に煌めく太陽は
The sun, sparkling with love
雲の上で燃えているか
Is it burning above the clouds?
北風にあおられて
Blown by the north wind
流す涙を隠しつつ
While hiding the tears I shed
明日に駆け出した
I dashed towards tomorrow
わため将軍
Watame Shogun
いぇーい！
Yay!
こんばんドドド～！
Konban-dododo~!
ホロライブ４期生、角巻わためです！ おー！
Hololive 4th Gen, Tsunomaki Watame here! Oh!
みんなー！
Everyone~!
見に来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you all for coming to watch!
今日は...
Today is...
だれの？
Whose?
誕生日でしょうか？ わための誕生日です！
Birthday is it? It's Watame's birthday!
ということで今日は、#わための誕生日2021 で
So today, using the hashtag #WatameBirthday2021
たくさんツイートしていただけると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you could tweet a lot!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for your support!
ふぅ〜...
Phew...
やれやれ、誕生日が始まっちまったぜ。
Good grief, the birthday has begun.
なぁ？
Right?
どんな一日になるのかな〜。
I wonder what kind of day it'll be.
楽しみだな〜。
I'm looking forward to it.
おや？
Oh?
わ、たくさんお祝いありがとうね！
Wow, thank you all for the celebrations!
おめでとうもありがとうね！
And thank you for the congratulations!
たくさんありがとうね！
Thank you so much!
いやー、これちょっと１時間ぐらいありますんでね、見てってね！
Well, we have about an hour ahead of us, so please stay tuned!
楽しんでってね！
Please enjoy!
最後まで絶対見てね！
Make sure to watch until the end!
頼む！ 頼む！
I beg you! I beg you!
一生のお願い！
My lifelong request!
うそ。
Oops.
あれ、今日は...
Wait, today is...
あの、おりゃ。
Um, oops.
きょ、今日はあれ...
T-Today is, you know...
なんか、あの、誰かからお呼びがかかる予定なんだけどな。
I'm supposed to be called by someone, though...
わため先輩！
Watame-senpai!
あ！この声は...
Oh! This voice is...
ぼ、ぼたんちゃん？
Bo... Botan-chan?
ちょっと行ってくるわ。
I'll go for a bit.
行ってきまーす！
I'm off!
わため先輩！
Watame-senpai!
はーい！
Hi!
ようこそ、私の研究室へ。
Welcome to my laboratory.
なんか怖いから、将軍の格好で来たよ。
It seemed a bit scary, so I came dressed as a shogun.
あ、本当だ。武装してる。
Oh, it's true. You're armed.
うん、武装してきたよ。
Yeah, I'm armed.
ちっ、これじゃオーブンに入ら...入らないじゃないか。
Geez, with this, you won't... won't fit in the oven.
オーブン？
Oven?
あの、わため先輩、ちょっと大変言いにくいんですが...
Um, Watame-senpai, it's a bit hard to say, but...
あの、その兜、ちょっと脱いでもらえません...？
Could you please take off that helmet?
いや、オーブンって言われて怖い...え？
Wait, you said "oven", that's scary... Eh?
あの、違います。オ、オーブンじゃないです。オーブンじゃないです。
No, no. O-Oven, it's not an oven. It's not an oven.
オーブンじゃない？今日オーブン使わない。
Not an oven? I'm not using the oven today.
本当に？
Really?
はい。
Yes.
脱いで大丈夫？
Is it okay if I take it off?
大丈夫です。大丈夫です。大丈夫だす。
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay-dasu.
じゃ、脱ごうかな。あ、ちょっと脱いで脱いで。ポイッと。
Then, I'll take it off. Oh, just take it off. (Pop)
はー、よかった。今日はちょっと私の...あ、大丈夫だすよ。
Phew, good. Today, at my... oh, it's okay-dasu.
大丈夫ですよ。大丈夫ですよ。今日私のね、ホームへようこそお越しいただきました。
It's okay. It's okay. Welcome to my home today.
キッチンあるんだね。
There's a kitchen.
あ、今日ちょっとね、キッチン、急遽ちょっとこしらえたんですよ。
Yeah, I quickly prepared this kitchen today.
急遽？
Quickly?
今日なんか、あ、なんか誰かの誕生日っていうのを聞いて、
I heard it's someone's birthday today...
あ、なんかちょっとキッチンあったほうがいいのかな、と思って。
So I thought it would be better to have a kitchen.
あ、なるほど。その人のために？
Oh, I see. For that person?
そうですね。ま、やっぱり誕生日といえば、美味しい料理に、
Right. Well, birthdays mean good food and...
ま、ケーキとかね。
well, cake and stuff.
そうだね。
That's right.
そう、だからちょっとケーキを作りたいな、と思ったんですよ。
Right, so I thought I'd like to make a cake.
なのでちょっとこうね、キッチンをこしらえたわけなんです。
That's why I prepared the kitchen.
なるほど。ケーキは？
I see. Where's the cake?
ただ、ケーキを作る前に、
Well, before making the cake...
ま、ね、せっかく今日こうやってわため先輩がさ、一緒にキッチンの周りにいてくれるということで、
Well, since Watame-senpai is here at the kitchen with me today...
ちょっとやりたいことをね。ありました。
There's something I want to do. I have it.
何？やりたいこと。
What? Something you want to do?
やっぱりこれなの？やりたいこと？
Is it this after all? Something you want to do?
やりたいことがありましたんで、ちょっとやっていきたいな、と思って。
There was something I wanted to do, so I'd like to do it.
なるほど。
I see.
じゃ、なのでちょっとついてきてもらっていいですかね。場所移動します。
So, could you follow me for a bit? We're moving locations.
先行って？あ、先行ったほうがいいですか？
Should I go first? Oh, should I go first?
しょうがないな。じゃ、ちょっとついてきてください。こっちです。
I guess I have to. Then, please follow me. It's this way.
大丈夫だろな...
I'm worried...
足元気をつけてください。
Please watch your step.
優しい。
How kind.
足元気をつけてください。ちょっとこの火の上を歩いてもらいます。
Please watch your step. I'll have you walk over this fire.
え？火の上？
Eh? Over fire?
火！あちっ、あちっ！
Fire! Hot, hot!
この火の上、えー、この火の上の屋上までちょっと。
Walk over this fire... to the rooftop of this building.
あちっ、あちっ、えー、なんでここ燃えてんの？怖っ！
Hot, hot! Why is it burning here? Scary!
いや、香ばしい匂いしてきましたね。
Well, it smells nice and savory, doesn't it?
いややっぱりね、あの、建物の中で今煙ってちょっと厳しいんですよ。
Well, you know, smoke inside a building is a bit tough these days.
そうなのね。
Is that so?
そうそう。だからやっぱりちょっと屋上でね、煙出すなら屋上ですから。
Yeah, so it's got to be the rooftop. If you're going to make smoke, it's the rooftop.
煙出すなら屋上？(laugh) やばいやばいやばい。やべーやべーやべー。聞こえてるぞー。
If you're going to make smoke, it's the rooftop? (laugh) Oh no, oh no. I can hear you!
じゃん。ここ、私のホームでございます。
Ta-da! This is my home.
お、初めて来たね。ここ初めて来た。初めて来た。屋上結構いいでしょ？
Oh, first time here. The rooftop is pretty good, right?
いいーね、開放感があって。いいーね、広いね。でしょ。
It's nice. It feels open. It's wide. Right?
ここで何をすると言うのかな。
So what shall we do here?
ま、やっぱりね、わた、これ？
Well, of course, Wata... this?
ふぁい！ふぁい！ふぁい！違う！違う！違う！
Fight! Fight! No! No! No!
わため先輩といえば私の中では、ま、歌っていうのもありますので、
When it comes to Watame-senpai, for me, there's "singing" too.
うん、うん。ちょっと今日は一緒に歌えたらいいな、と。
So I thought it would be nice if we could sing together today.
お！いいんですか逆に。一緒に、歌わせてもらっていいんですか？
Oh! Is that okay? On the contrary, is it okay for me to sing with you?
ぜひお願いします。
Please, by all means.
やったー！
Yay!
ということで、今日はわため先輩と一緒に歌わせていただきます。
So today I will be singing with Watame-senpai.
よろしくお願いします。
Please treat me well.
お願いします。私がゲストみたい。お願いします！
Please treat me well. It's like I'm the guest.
じゃあ、行きますか。はい。せーの！
Then, shall we go? One, two!
やさしい気持ち！
Kind Feelings!
やさしい気持ち
作詞・作曲：Chara
Kind Feelings
Lyrics/Composition: Chara
泣けない女のやさしい気持ちを
The kind feelings of a woman who cannot cry
あなたがたくさん知るのよ
You will get to know them well
無邪気な心であたしを笑顔へ導いてほしいの
I want you to lead me to a smile with an innocent heart
ぎゅっとあたしを抱きしめて
Hold me tight
...不機嫌な音符があなたの理想だとしてもこの愛が...
...Even if moody notes are your ideal, this love...
...自由を壊して
...breaks through freedom.
でも勝手だって叱らないで
But please don't scold me for being selfish.
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands.
手をずっとこうしてたいの
I want to keep holding hands like this forever.
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands.
手をずっとこうしてたいの
I want to keep holding hands like this forever.
慣れない私とあなたの間に こんなにわがままがいいですか?
Between the unfamiliar me and you, is it okay to be this selfish?
言葉で言わなきゃ今すぐ言わなきゃ そんなの知らないわ
You have to say it in words, right now. I don't know anything about that.
もう私を止めないで
Don't stop me anymore.
踊ろう毎日ちゃんとこの手を胸を
Let's dance every day, keeping our hands and hearts...
輝かせてよなあなたのその存在
...shining, through your very existence.
もう私は止められない
I can't be stopped anymore.
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands.
手をずっとこうしてたいの
I want to keep holding hands like this forever.
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands.
手をずっとこうしてたいの
I want to keep holding hands like this forever.
お願い
Please.
ぎゅっと私を抱きしめて
Hold me tight.
もう私を離さないで
Never let me go.
手をつなごう
Let's hold hands.
泣いても鳴いてもキスしてもいいから色々してたいわ
Whether I cry, call out, or kiss you, I want to do all sorts of things.
もう私を止めないで
Don't stop me anymore.
あ！あ！やべ！
Ah! Ah! Crap!
わためちゃん、タレ買い忘れた。 え？
Watame-chan, I forgot the sauce. Eh?
ちょっと買ってきていいですか？
Can I go buy some really quick?
急だね！
That's so sudden!
あの、何味が良いですか？ タレ？
Um, what flavor do you want? Sauce?
タレです。
The sauce.
必要、それ？ 必要です。
Is it necessary? It's necessary.
必要？ 必要です。
Necessary? It's necessary.
ほんじゃ、あー、おろしがいいかな。
Well then, ah, maybe grated radish flavor?
あ、オッケーです！ おろしがいいかな。
Ah, okay! Grated radish would be good.
大根たっぷり買ってきます！
I'll buy lots of daikon radish!
おー、いってらっしゃい。
Oh, see you later.
急にタレ買いに行く人おる？
Is there anyone else who'd suddenly go buy sauce?
わためー！ はあちゃまー！ わためー！
Watame! Haachama! Watame!
はあちゃまの、はあちゃまの…
Haachama's, Haachama's...
はあちゃまの残像が見える！
I can see Haachama's afterimage!
ちょっと、行ってくるわ！
Wait, I'm going too!
うわあああ！
Uwaaaa!
わため！はあちゃま！今行くぞ！ はあああ！わためー！はあちゃまー！
Watame! Haachama! Here I come! Haaaaa! Watame! Haachama!
よっ！牧場へいらっしゃい！
Yo! Welcome to the ranch!
よったんじゃねー！ はい！
Don't 'yo' me! Yes!
今日はね、あの、わためを出荷するためにここに呼んできましたと。
Today, I've called you here to ship you out, Watame.
今日めでたい日ですよ！
Today is a day for celebration!
わためおめでとう！
Happy birthday, Watame!
ありがとう！ わためおめでとう！
Thank you! Happy birthday, Watame!
ありがとう。出荷やだ！
Thank you. I don't want to be shipped!
出荷！出荷！ 出荷やだ！
Shipping! Shipping! I don't want to be shipped!
あ、そんなこんなでね。 まあさすがにはあちゃまも… 誕生日のわためにね、 そんな出荷なんてしないわよ、本当に。
Well, you know. Even Haachama wouldn't really ship Watame out on her birthday, really.
そうだよね！
Right!
そんなに鬼じゃないから。
I'm not that much of a demon.
だから、はあちゃま、ケーキを作ってきました！
So, Haachama made a cake for you!
やったー！ケーキを作った？
Yay! You made a cake?
うん。
Yeah.
何入ってんのかな？
I wonder what's in it?
わためのために！
For Watame's sake!
あー、ケーキ作ってきたよー
Ah, I made a cake!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
色んな愛も込めて、
I put a lot of love into it...
色んなたくさん愛も込めて、作ってきたんで
I put a lot of love into it and made it.
何入れたー？
What's in it?
ちょっと出したいと思います。
I'll take it out.
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
おっ！
Oh!
おいしそー
It looks delicious!
チーズケーキだね
It's a cheesecake.
チーズケーキかな？
Maybe it's a cheesecake?
かな？
Maybe?
多分
Maybe.
かな？
Maybe?
あー！
Ah!
うーん...
Umm...
ケーキ食べたい？
Do you want to eat the cake?
食べたい食べたい
I want to eat it! I want to eat it!
そんなに食べたいなら...
If you want to eat it that much...
あーおいしそう
Ah, it looks delicious.
うぇー
Woah!
ちゃんと刺して刺して
Stab it properly, stab it.
取れない...あ、取れた！
I can't take it... Oh, I got it!
ナイスナイスナイス！
Nice, nice, nice!
はい。
Here.
あーん。
Ahn.
もぐもぐもぐもぐ。
Yum, yum, yum, yum.
美味しい？
Is it good?
はちゃまも食べなこれ。
Haachama should eat this too.
はい、はーちゃま！
Here, Haachama!
もぐもぐもぐもぐ。
Yum, yum, yum, yum.
うまいね！
It's good!
うまい、うまい。
Good, good.
なんかもう一個取れたわ。
I took another piece.
どうぞ。
Here.
もぐもぐもぐもぐ。
Yum, yum, yum, yum.
はい、うまい。
Yes, it's good.
うまい、うまい。
Good, good.
はい、ヤムヤム。
Yes, yummy!
ありがとう、ケーキ。
Thanks for the cake.
いぇーい！
Yay!
ケーキ、バイバーイ！
Bye-bye cake!
え、急に、まだ残ってた、いいのかな？
Wait, everything's so sudden, there's some left, is that okay?
ケーキ、バイバーイ！
Bye-bye cake!
あ、
Ah,
あ、消えちゃった。あれ？
Ah, it's gone. Huh?
あれ？
Huh?
何なった？
What happened?
じゃあそろそろ歌うか。
Well, shall we sing soon?
なんか全てが急なんだけど！
Everything is so sudden!
歌うか！歌うか！
Let's sing! Let's sing!
え、でもここじゃちょっとな...雰囲気出ないと思うんだよ。
Well, here is a bit... I don't think it sets the mood.
え、わためちゃん、どこかに連れてってくれるの？
Watame-chan, will you take me somewhere?
いいよ。じゃあ、一緒にジャンプして。
Sure. Then, let's jump together.
せーの。
Ready...
せーの！
Ready, set!
はっ！
Hah!
わための聖地！
Watame's sacred place!
いらっしゃいませ！
Welcome!
やったー！見たかったんだよなー！
Yay! I wanted to see this!
いぇーい！
Yay!
瞬間移動！
Instant teleportation!
瞬間移動。なんかあるよ、ここに。
Instant teleportation. Something is over there.
ヤカンじゃんそれ！
That's a kettle!
形、ヤカンっぽいけど。
The shape looks like a kettle though.
金ヤカン。
Golden kettle.
おっけー。
Okay.
おっけー？そこで歌うのかい？
Okay? Are you going to sing there?
鑑賞しとくよ、はあとも。
I'll just watch, Haato will.
だめだよ。一緒に歌うんだから。
No, we're singing together!
おっけー。
Okay.
デュエットするんだから。
Because we're doing a duet!
デュエット。
Duet!
デュエットするか。
Shall we duet?
しよう。
Let's do it.
頼む。
Please.
何の歌うたう？
What song shall we sing?
せーの、あの歌？
Ready? That song.
せーの、あれ歌う？
Ready? Shall we sing that?
行く？
Shall we go?
Are we going?
もう行っちゃう？
Ready to go?
行っちゃう？
Let's do it!
行くのかい、行かないのかい？
Are we doing it or not?
準備できた？
Ready?
準備できたよ。
I'm ready.
準備できた？
Are you ready?
おっけー。
Okay.
せーの！
Ready, set!
ハッピーシンセサイザ！
Happy Synthesizer!
ハッピーシンセサイザ
作詞・作曲:BETTI
Happy Synthesizer
Lyrics & Music: BETTI
ハッピーシンセサイザ　君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your heart
届くようなメロディ　奏でるよ
A melody will play and reach you
儚く散った　淡い片思い
A fleeting, faint unrequited love
笑い話だね　今となれば
It's a joke now, thinking back
見るもの全て　輝いて見えた
Everything I saw seemed to sparkle
あの日々が綺麗に　笑ってるよ
Those days are laughing beautifully
我慢することだけ　覚えなきゃいけないの？
Do I have to learn how to just endure?
大人になってそうだね　ならなくていいよ
If that means becoming an adult, I don't need it
知らないことばかり　知らないなんて言えなくて
So many things I don't know, but I couldn't say I don't know
大変お似合いで　嘘ついてごめんね
I'm sorry for lying and saying it suits you
ハッピーシンセサイザ　君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your heart
届くようなメロディ　奏でるよ
A melody will play and reach you
つまらない建前や　ヤなこと全部
Boring pretenses and all the bad things
消してあげるから　この音で
I'll make them disappear with this sound
何の取り柄もない　僕にただひとつ
I have no special qualities, but there's one thing
少しだけだけど　できること
Just one thing I can do, even if it's small
心躍らせる　飾らない言葉
Simple words that make your heart dance
電子音で　伝えるよ
I'll convey them with electronic sounds
好きになること　理屈なんかじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic
こじつけなんてもう　いらないんじゃない？
I don't think we need forced excuses anymore
時代のせいと　諦めたらそこまで
If you blame the times and give up, that's it
踏み出さなくちゃ　何も始まらない
Nothing starts unless you take a step
ごめんね夜遅く　寝るところだったでしょう？
Sorry for calling late at night, you were about to sleep, right?
驚いた僕も　駆け出そうとしてた
Surprised, I was also about to start running
心の裏側を　くすぐられてるような
It feels like the back of my heart is being tickled
惹かれ合う二人に　幸せな音を
Happy sounds for the two of us drawn to each other
ハッピーシンセサイザ　ほらね　楽しくなるよ
Happy synthesizer, see? It'll make you feel better
涙ぬぐうメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that'll wipe away your tears
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？別に
You don't have to try so hard to be strong, you know?
自分に素直になればいい
It's fine to just be honest with yourself
何の取り柄もない　僕にただひとつ
To me, someone with no redeeming qualities, there's just one thing
少しだけできること
That I can do, just a little bit
ちょっと照れるような　単純な気持ち
These simple feelings, a bit embarrassing
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them through electronic sounds
ハッピーシンセサイザ　君の胸の奥まで
Happy synthesizer, into the depths of your heart
届くようなメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that'll reach you
つまらない建前や　ヤなこと全部
All those boring pretenses and nasty things
消してあげるから　この音で
I'll erase them all with this sound
何の取り柄もない　僕にただひとつ
To me, someone with no redeeming qualities, there's just one thing
少しだけできること
That I can do, just a little bit
心躍らせる　飾らない言葉
Unadorned words to make your heart dance
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them through electronic sounds
ハッピーシンセサイザ　ほらね　楽しくなるよ
Happy synthesizer, see? It'll make you feel better
涙ぬぐうメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that'll wipe away your tears
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？別に
You don't have to try so hard to be strong, you know?
自分に素直になればいい
It's fine to just be honest with yourself
何の取り柄もない　僕にただひとつ
To me, someone with no redeeming qualities, there's just one thing
少しだけできること
That I can do, just a little bit
ちょっと照れるような　単純な気持ち
These simple feelings, a bit embarrassing
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them through electronic sounds
イエーイ！
Yay!
楽しかったねー！
That was fun!
楽しかったー！
So much fun!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、ただいまー。
Ah, I'm back.
あ、おかえりー。
Ah, welcome back.
あれ？ぼたんちゃん？
Wait, Botan-chan?
どうしてこの場所に…？
How did you find this place...?
匂いでなんか分かっちゃった。
I kind of figured it out by the smell.
匂いで分かっちゃった！？
By the smell!?
匂いで分かっちゃった。え、これわための地元？
By the smell. Is this Watame's hometown?
そうだよ！あ、やべ、バレた！
That's right! Oh no, I've been found!
また遊びに来るよ。
I'll come visit again.
バレたバレたー！
I've been found out!
生息地がバレたー！
My habitat has been discovered!
また遊びに来ちゃおうかなー。
Maybe I'll come visit again.
狙われてるよー、わためー。
You're being targeted, Watame.
タレ持ってきたよ。
I brought some dipping sauce.
はあちゃまも後でタレ渡すね。
Haachama, I'll give you some sauce later too.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
じゃあさ、今日が最後になるかもしれないからさ…
Well, since today might be the last time...
記念撮影しとく？
Shall we take a commemorative photo?
撮っとく？いいかな？
Shall we? Is that okay?
しようか。
Let's do it.
スクショタイムってやつしてもいいかな？
Can we have a screenshot time?
あ、いいですよ。
Oh, sure.
じゃあ、３人でまず…
Okay, the three of us first...
撮る？どんなポーズがいい？
Take it? What kind of pose should we do?
どうする？なんかコメントとかでも…
What should we do? Maybe from the comments...
そうね、コメント見たいポーズとかあったらぜひ。
Right, if there are any poses you want to see, let us know in the comments.
何がいい？
What would be good?
何がいい？草しかねえ！
What would be good? There's nothing but 'Kusa' (grass)!
「草」のポーズ！？
The 'Kusa' pose!?
「草」のポーズ！そのポーズ！
The 'Kusa' pose! That pose!
草、草、わさ、わさ…
Kusa, kusa, rustle, rustle...
なんだこれ。
What is this?
せっかく集まったのに「草」のポーズ！
We finally got together and we're doing the 'Kusa' pose!
「草」のポーズ！いい？
The 'Kusa' pose! Is this okay?
なんかある？
Anything else?
ある？わため先輩、なんかあります？撮りたいやつ。
Is there? Watame-senpai, is there anything you want to take?
つのドリル！
Tsuno Drill (Horn Drill)!
つのドリル！食らってよ、つのドリル！
Tsuno Drill! Take this, Tsuno Drill!
あ、いいよ。
Oh, sure.
「うわあー」って言って！
Say 'Whoaaa'!
うわあー！待って待って！まだやってないって！
Whoaaa! Wait, wait! I haven't done it yet!
行くよー！
Here I go!
はい！
Yes!
つのドリル！
Tsuno Drill!
したたたたたたー！
Shtatatatata!
痛快、痛快！
Refreshing, refreshing!
痛快、痛快！これ気持ちいいー。
Refreshing, refreshing! This feels good.
これでいいの！？
Is this really okay!?
いいのか？決まったー。
Is it? It's decided.
ちょっと！やめてー！
Hey! Stop it!
地元でいいのか、こんな喧嘩して！
Is it okay to fight like this in your hometown!
やっちまおうぜー！
Let's do it!
うわあー！おらおらおらおらー！やべえ！食べられるー！
Whoaaa! Ora ora ora ora! Oh no! I'm gonna be eaten!
このままハート作ろうぜ。
Let's make a heart like this.
あ、いいよ！
Oh, sure!
ハート作ろう。命大事に。
Let's make a heart. Treasure your life.
命大事に。なんか回復してきた。
Treasure your life. I feel like I'm recovering.
あ、本当？よかったよかった。
Oh, really? That's good.
ＨＰ、イエーイ！
HP, yay!
よしよしよしよし、いいぞ。回復してきた。ひでえ、ひでえな。
Good, good, good. I'm recovering. That's terrible.
ツーショットとか撮る？
Shall we take some two-shots?
あ、じゃあツーショット撮る。私あれするよ、カメラマンするよ。
Oh, then let's take two-shots. I'll be the photographer.
お、ししろカメラマン！
Oh, Shishiro the photographer!
ししろカメラマンにお願いしますよ！
We're counting on you, Photographer Shishiro!
ししろカメラマン、下から行く派だけどいいかな？
Photographer Shishiro likes to shoot from below, is that okay?
何！？ローアングルだと！？
What!? A low angle!?
ししろカメラマンは下から…
Photographer Shishiro from below...
いやーん！何ー！？下から撮らないでー！
Nooo! What!? Don't shoot from below!
下から行くよー！
Going from below!
いやーん！見ちゃダメー！
Nooo! Don't look!
見せんな、見せんな！うわあー！やめてくださーい！
Don't show it, don't show it! Whoaaa! Please stop!
そんなそんなそんなそんな...
No way, no way, no way, no way...
あ、ダブルピース？
Ah, double peace?
ダブルピース。
Double peace.
あ、いいね。
Ah, that's good.
イエーイ！はい！いいね。いいね。はい。
Yay! Yes! Good. Good. Yes.
投げキッスして、投げキッス。
Give me a blowing kiss, a blowing kiss.
投げキッス。
Blowing kiss.
んま んま んま んま んま...
Mwah mwah mwah mwah mwah...
あーいいね。いい感じ。
Ah, nice. Looking good.
いい感じよ。
It's looking good.
やっぱね、ちょっと後ろとかも、なんかこう横とか後ろとか。
As I thought, maybe from the back too, like from the side or back.
後ろ？
Back?
後ろ。こっちこっち。
Back. This way, this way.
あ、こっちだった。
Ah, it was this way.
どっちどっち？
Which way?
こっちこっち。こっち？こっち？
This way, this way. This way? This way?
じゃあ、足はこうするわ。
Then, I'll do this with my legs.
振り向いてよ、振り向いてよ。
Turn around, turn around.
いいよ。
Okay.
振り向け様。
Turning around.
呼んでんじゃん。
I'm calling you.
二人ともこっち向いて。
Both of you, look this way.
なに？なに？呼んだ？どうしたの？
What? What? Did you call? What's wrong?
みんな右から向いちゃったのね。
Everyone turned from the right, huh.
あ、こっち？
Ah, this way?
こう？
Like this?
二人でふぁーって。
The two of you, like 'fuwa' (softly).
オーケー。
OK.
二人とも、こっち向いて。テイク２。
Both of you, look this way. Take 2.
はーい！
Yes!
あー、かわいい。これはかわいい。いいね。
Ah, cute. This is cute. Nice.
イエーイ！イエーイ！
Yay! Yay!
ししろん交換する？
Shishiron, want to swap?
あ、交換する？オーケー。
Ah, swap? OK.
見守っててよ。一旦私して。
Watch me. Let's do me for a bit.
オーケーオーケー。
OK OK.
ごめんね。どんなのが撮りたい？
Sorry. What kind of photo do you want to take?
どんなのがいい？どんなのがいい？
What kind is good? What kind is good?
やっぱローアングルから。
As expected, from a low angle.
ローアングル？
Low angle?
そんなー！そんなー！そんなー！そんなー！やめてください！やめてください！
No way! No way! No way! No way! Please stop! Please stop!
いいねいいね。
Nice, nice.
やめてください！
Please stop!
イエーイ！アハハハ！
Yay! Ahahaha!
後ろからも撮るか？
Shall we take some from the back too?
あ、後ろ撮る？オーケー。
Ah, from the back? OK.
どうぞ。
Go ahead.
さ...
Well...
あ、分かった分かった。え、狙われてる。
Ah, I get it, I get it. Eh, being targeted.
なんてった？食べられそうになってるわためっていう構図やろう。
What was it? The composition where Watame is about to be eaten, right?
あ、いいね。いいのか？
Ah, nice. Is it okay?
こっちこっち。
This way, this way.
どっち？
Which way?
わため様こっちじゃない？
Watame-sama, isn't it this way?
そうね。
True.
ここで、顔、カメラ目線で。
Here, face, looking at the camera.
うん。こっちだ。
Yeah. This way.
あ、そうそうそう。あ、顔やばい。
Ah, right right right. Ah, that face is crazy.
やばい！
It's crazy!
あ、いいよいいよ、いいよ。いいよ。いいよ。
Ah, good, good, good. Good. Good.
あ、おしまいだ。
Ah, it's the end.
おしまいだ！
It's the end!
いい感じいい感じ。
Good vibe, good vibe.
イエーイ！
Yay!
いいねいいね。オーケーオーケー。他。他も撮りたい？
Nice, nice. OK OK. Others. Want to take others too?
どうしようだ。もっとなんか...
What should we do? More like...
なんか...
Something...
ねねのてぇてぇやつ？
Nene's wholesome thing?
てぇてぇやつ。
The wholesome thing.
おおー！イエーイ！いいね。イエーイ！
Ooh! Yay! Nice. Yay!
いいね。イエーイ！
Nice. Yay!
うぇい。ビリビリビリビリ。
Wei. (sounds of velcro)
ごめんね。ごめんね。
Sorry. Sorry.
バリバリの服。ごめんね。
Velcro clothes. Sorry.
な、大丈夫？服取れそう？大丈夫、服脱げなーい。
Wait, is it okay? Are the clothes coming off? It's okay, the clothes won't come off.
放送事故だよ。
It's a broadcasting accident.
ちょっとわため先輩の服バリバリ...
Watame-senpai's clothes are like bari bari...
ごめん、マジックテープで貼ってたのね。
Sorry, they were attached with velcro, weren't they.
あ？なんだ？
Huh? What?
あ、この声は！バカタレ共！
Ah, that voice! The Bakatare bunch!
あら、もしかして。
Oh, perhaps.
呼ばれちゃった。ちょっと呼ばれてるみたいだから、一緒に行ってくるわ。
I was called. It seems like I'm being called, so I'll go with them.
分かった。じゃあ、またな。
Got it. See you then.
バイバイ。ありがとうね。
Bye-bye. Thanks.
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy birthday!
バカタレです。ありがとう。
It's Bakatare. Thank you.
わためー！わためー！
Watame! Watame!
おおー！来た来た来た！
Oh! Here I come!
お待たせ！
Thanks for waiting!
遅いよ！
You're late!
お腹空かせて待ってたんだからなー！
I've been waiting with an empty stomach!
そう、お腹ペコペコだよ。
Yeah, my stomach is growling.
何食べる？ジンギスカンでしょ？
What are we eating? Genghis Khan, right?
あちゃちゃちゃ。ケーキ、とりあえずケーキケーキ。
Ah, wait. Cake, first of all cake cake.
あ、ケーキケーキケーキ！
Ah, cake cake cake!
わためのわためから、そう、ケーキ。
From Watame's belly, yeah, cake.
そうね、な。ケーキ食べようなー！
Right. Let's eat cake!
じゃあ、ケーキを食べる前に。
Then, before eating cake.
腹減らそうぜ！
Let's work up an appetite!
お、確かにね。運動は大事だね。
Oh, certainly. Exercise is important.
運動は大事だな。おー。
Exercise is important. Oh.
運動な。
Exercise, right.
運動するぞ。
Let's exercise.
ラジオ体操かな？
Radio calisthenics, maybe?
ミュージック...スタァート！
Music... Start!
ナンダカンダ
作詞:GAKU-MC/作曲:浅倉 大介
Nanda Kanda
Lyrics: GAKU-MC / Music: Daisuke Asakura
自分よりツイてない
Someone less lucky than me
誰か見て安心かい
Do you feel relieved seeing them?
自分だけは例外
Thinking you're the only exception
思い込んで勝手言った
Believing that and speaking selfishly
いつからか昼と夜が
Since when did day and night
行き違った生活で
Pass each other in my life?
塞ぎ込まないでどうか
Please don't get depressed
目を覚まして道を探せ
Wake up and find your path
なんだかんだ叫んだって
No matter what you scream
やりたいことやるだけさ
You just do what you want to do
やるべきです
You should do it
あんたなんだ 次の番は
It's you, you're next
やりがいあふれるレースです
It's a rewarding race
寝不足で疲労を
Fatigue from lack of sleep
疲れすぎてどうしようと
Wondering what to do when you're too tired
伺う顔色も
Gauging reactions
気にしすぎてこの鼓動
Caring too much, this heartbeat
はみ出す勇気をどうか
Please, the courage to stand out
絞り出して立ち上がれ
Squeeze it out and stand up
ほんの少しの気合だ
It's just a little bit of fighting spirit
目を覚まさなくちゃ 笑え
You've got to wake up, smile
なんだかんだ夢見たって
Despite dreaming of this or that
問題ない世の中で
In a world where it's no problem
あんたなんだ 次の番は
It's you, you're next
みんなに愛を振りまいて
Spread love to everyone
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
声出せー！
Let me hear your voices!
おー！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Oh! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もっともっとー！
More, more!
レッツゴー！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Let's go! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
いいね！ サンキュー！ フゥー！
Nice! Thank you! Foo!
あるべきはずの明日に
Towards the tomorrow that should be
派手すぎるテレビの前
In front of the overly flashy TV
平和ボケしてませんか
Are you numbed by peace?
目を覚ませ今だここで
Wake up, right here, right now
なんだかんだ叫んだって
Despite shouting this or that
やりたいことやるべきです
You should do what you want to do
あんたなんだ 次の番は
It's you, you're next
みんなに愛を振りまいて
Spread love to everyone
なんだかんだ夢見たって
Despite dreaming of this or that
問題ない世の中で
In a world where it's no problem
あんたなんだ 次の番は
It's you, you're next
夢が叶う大成功です
It's a huge success where dreams come true
はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はあー、はあー。
*Panting*
楽しかったー！
That was fun!
いやもう全曲よ。
Wow, that was the whole song.
なんだかんだ。
Nanda Kanda.
バッチリでしょう。
It was perfect, right?
いやバッチリだったけども。
Yeah, it was spot on.
バッチリだったでしょう。
It was spot on, right?
すごいバッチリだったよ。
It was totally spot on.
ねえ、みんなもそう思うよな！
Right, everyone thinks so too!
な！ な！
Right! Right!
良い曲なんだな。
It's a good song.
バカ誰度も入ってたよな。
Bakatare-ness was in there too.
バカ誰なんだな。
Bakatare indeed.
なんてったってバカ誰なんだな。
After all, it's Bakatare.
なんてったって素晴らしい選曲だね。
After all, what a great song choice.
ねえ。とっても良かったね。
Yeah. It was really good.
いやめちゃ楽しかった。
Man, that was so much fun.
いやめっちゃ良かった、ありがとう。
Yeah, it was great, thank you.
本当にみんなと一緒に歌えて。
Really, being able to sing with everyone.
本当にありがとう。 おめでとう！
Thank you so much. Congratulations!
さてさて、わためぇよ。
Well now, Watame.
はい。
Yes.
今日は、わためぇの、お誕生日、ですね？
Today is Watame's birthday, right?
ですよね！
Right!
そう！
Yes!
で、こうしてライブ一緒にね、やったんですけども。
And we did this live together.
まあ、はっ、我々からね。
Well, ha, from us...
うん。
Yeah.
やっぱり、わためぇに。
To Watame, of course.
ほ。
Oh?
記念すべき日なので、プレゼントを！
Since it's a commemorative day, a present!
用意させていただきましたー！
We've prepared one for you!
はい、そして、なんと、プレゼント、用意してまーす！
Yes, and what's more, we have a present ready!
ティリリリリ...
Drum roll sound
何！？
What!?
ということで、スタッフさん持ってきてくださーい！
So, staff, please bring it over!
ティティティ...
Drum roll continues
ええ、本当に？ 見たい！
Eh, really? I want to see!
何？
What is it?
はい、ということで。 あ、すごい浮いてる、浮いてる、浮いてる！
Alright, here it is. Oh wow, it's floating!
浮いてる！
It's floating!
え！？
Eh!?
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
うわあ、暴れん坊だ。
Whoa, it's a wild one.
わためぇに、プレゼントです！
For Watame, a present!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ええー！
Ehhh!?
フレアと私からの、プレゼントだよ！
A present from Flare and me!
プレゼントだよ！
It's a present!
ええー！ 本当！？
Ehhh!? Really!?
ええー！
Ehhh!?
え、何も聞かされてなかった、これ！
Eh, I wasn't told anything about this!
当たり前だろ、サプライズなんだからよ！
Of course not, it's a surprise!
言っちゃ意味ないだろ。
There's no point if we tell you.
そうだよ。
That's right.
ええー！
Ehhh!?
おめでとう、わためぇ！ おめでとう！
Congratulations, Watame! Congratulations!
これ、開けていいの？
Can I open this?
開けていいよ。
You can open it.
開けてもいいよ、ぜひ開けて。
You can open it. Please open it.
今開けていいの？
Can I open it now?
いいよ、いいよ。
Go ahead, go ahead.
しゃがんで開けて。
Crouch down and open it.
絵面を気にしてるぞ。
Mind the camera shot.
しゃがんで開けていいよ。
You can crouch down and open it.
開けていいの？
Can I open it?
ちょっとね、色とか言っちゃうとちょっとあれだから。
If we mention the color or something...
もう見て確認してもらって。
Just look and check for yourself.
ええー！ 可愛いー！
Ehhh!? It's cute!
可愛い！
So cute!
やったー！
Yay!
可愛いものが入ってるでしょう？
There's something cute inside, right?
わためぇに似合うと思ったんだー。 ねー。
We thought it would suit Watame. Right.
いつ選んだの？
When did you pick this?
いつだろうねえ。
I wonder when.
いつだろうね。 フレアとちょっと一緒にね。
I wonder when. Together with Flare.
そう、わためぇどれが良いかなって。
Yeah, thinking about which one would be good for Watame.
これだなーって選んだの。
We picked it out like, "This is it!"
そう、選んだ。
Yeah, we did.
ええー！
Ehhh!?
良かった〜
I'm glad you liked it!
良かったら使ってくれい
Please use it if you like.
使ってね
Use it, okay?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということでね、わためライブと
And so, it was the Watame live and...
わためのサプライズでしたー！
...the surprise for Watame!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
嬉しいんじゃ〜
I'm so happy...
この後もわため歌うんでしょ？
You're singing more after this, right?
はい！
Yes!
まだまだ盛り上がってってくださーいな
Please keep getting hyped!
はい！ありがとー！
Yes! Thank you!
じゃあプレゼントは置いといて...
Well, let's put the present aside...
はい、置いてもらって...
Yes, have it placed...
置いとこう、持っとこうか？わための部屋に。
Let's put it down, or should we take it? To Watame's room.
あ、持っとこうか。シュパッて消えるかな？
Oh, should we? Will it disappear with a 'pop'?
あ、そこに置いとく？
Oh, put it there?
後でスタッフさんがいい感じに回収してくれると思います
I think the staff will collect it nicely later.
ありがとう本当に
Thank you, really.
いいんだよ、嬉しいんじゃー
It's okay, I'm so happy.
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
わためさん、記念撮影とかしたいんだけど...
Watame-san, we want to take commemorative photos...
いいのかい？お、いいかな？
Is it okay? Oh, is it?
みんな、撮りたいよな！
Everyone wants to take them, right!
あー！
Ah!
や、やるか！撮ろうかと思ってたけど
Yeah, let's do it! I was thinking of taking some too.
まだまだ残ってあげて！
Please stay a bit longer!
頼む！お願い！一緒にお願い！
Please! I beg you! Together, please!
一緒した！嘘でしょｗ 嘘だよｗ
We did! You're kidding lol. It's a lie lol.
撮影するか！お願いします！
Let's take photos! Please!
ハイ撮ってくれー！よいしょー！イェーイ！
Hi, take the photos! Yoisho! Yay!
イェーイ！いいねいいね！イェーイ！
Yay! Nice, nice! Yay!
限界まで！イェーイ！限界まで！
To the limit! Yay! To the limit!
ふー！ねぇ、近寄りすぎてるかい？撮ってくれてますかー？
Phew! Hey, are we too close? Are you taking them?
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
角巻ドリルした！下まで角巻ドリルした！
I did the Tsunomaki Drill! All the way down, Tsunomaki Drill!
耳ドリルした！耳ドリルした！
I did the Ear Drill! Ear Drill!
耳ドリルしてくれ！耳ドリルしたのかな？
Do the Ear Drill! Did they do it?
撮ってくれましたかな？かな？イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Did you take them? Yay! Yay! Yay!
下、下、下だわため。主役はわため！
Down, down, get down Watame. The star is Watame!
イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
や、良い感じじゃない？
Yeah, isn't it great?
余は満足じゃ！満足か！
I am satisfied! You are satisfied!
はぁ〜良かったですわため姫よ。ここで終わりにしようか。
Haa, I'm glad Princess Watame. Shall we end it here?
あー、もう終わりか。早いんじゃー。
Ah, it's over already. So soon.
や、頑張ってくださいこの後もソロライブ！
Well, good luck with the solo live after this!
頑張ってね！ありがとう！みなぎってきた！イェーイ！
Good luck! Thank you! I'm pumped up! Yay!
じゃあ行くか我々は。帰るか。帰っちゃうか。
Well, shall we go. Let's head back. We're leaving.
じゃーなー！また後でなー！バイバイ！
See ya! Later! Bye-bye!
みんなーー！嬉しいんじゃーーー！！
Everyone! I'm so happy!!
もう、ぼたんちゃんとか、はあちゃまとか、
Having Botan-chan, Haachama, and...
バカタレ共にお祝いしてもらって...
...the Bakatare trio celebrate for me...
本当に嬉しい、あと今時間空けてくれて、
I'm truly happy. And to everyone who made time,
こうやって配信を見てくれてるみんなも、本当にありがとうございます！
and is watching this stream right now, thank you so much!
いやここで泣いたらいかんのや...
No, I shouldn't cry here...
本当にみんな、いつも応援してくれてありがとう！ありがとう！
Truly, everyone, thank you for always supporting me! Thank you!
この後はね、大事な、大事なお知らせとか、
After this, I have important, very important announcements and...
あの、情報量たくさんありますので...
...lots of information, so...
ちょっとその前に、あの、ソロでも歌わせてもらったりして...
But before that, I'll be singing solo...
そのあと告知をさせてもらっても、いいでしょうかーーー！！
And after that, would it be okay if I make some announcements?!
コメント見てるでー！
I'm looking at the comments!
わ、スパチャもありがとうね！
Wow, thanks for the super chats too!
メンバーシップに入ってくれた人も本当にありがとうございます！
To those who joined the membership, thank you so much!
サイリウム、あのスタンプで振れるので、
You can wave penlights with stamps, so
よかったら、いっぱい振ってってください。お願いします！
please wave them a lot if you'd like. Please!
いいよ、いい玉！わ、いっぱいいって！
Good, good balls of light! Wow, go for it!
じゃあ、ちょっと感謝の気持ちを込めて、
Well then, with all my gratitude,
歌わせていただきたいなと思います！
I'd like to sing!
まず１曲目！
First song!
夜もすがら君想ふ！
Yomosugara Kimi Omou!
夜もすがら君想ふ
作詞・作曲：TOKO TOKO
Yomosugara Kimi Omou
Lyrics/Composition: TOKOTOKO
あぁ僕が生まれる前よりも
Ah, from long before I was born
ずっと昔から続くように
As if it's been continuing forever
そういつも傷付け合って
Yes, always hurting each other
...傷つけ合ってまた 愛し合うのさ
...hurt each other and then love each other again.
結婚や仕事のトークに またちょっと疲れてたとしても
Even if you're a bit tired of talk about marriage or work,
そう僕も他人事なんかじゃない 分かってるのさ
Yeah, it's not someone else's business to me either, I know that.
明けない夜はないと 夜明け前がただ暗いと
That there's no night that doesn't end, that it's just dark before dawn.
この先に待つ明日が そんなに輝くもんかな
I wonder if the tomorrow waiting ahead will really shine that much.
今 I Love You で始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれよ
Now, shine more light on us who start with 'I Love You'.
変わらない愛や希望の類も まだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in things like unchanging love and hope.
ほら I Miss You で諦めモードでも OK 飛ばしていけよ
Look, even if it's 'I Miss You' and resignation mode, it's OK, keep going.
時代が食らい未来が待ち受けど 愛を歌おう
Though the times are harsh and the future awaits, let's sing of love.
みんな楽しんでってな！
Everyone, have fun!
アボカドのトロに足ることで いつも悩んだりしてるのは
The reason I'm always worrying about it being like fatty tuna or avocado...
言っちゃえばアダムとイブからも 決まってたのさ
If I say so, it was decided since Adam and Eve.
なんとなく恋に落ちて いつの間にか本気だって
Somehow falling in love, and before I knew it, I was serious.
張り裂けそうな胸の奥は 打ち明けなくちゃな
I have to confess what's deep in my bursting heart.
今 I Love You で始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれよ
Now, shine more light on us who start with 'I Love You'.
イメージ通りに運ばぬとしても 信じてみたいのさ
Even if things don't go as imagined, I want to try believing.
ほら I Miss You って賞味期限がある Oh Yes 急かしてくれよ
Look, 'I Miss You' has an expiration date, Oh Yes, hurry me up.
時代が食らい未来が待ち受けど 愛を歌おう
Though the times are harsh and the future awaits, let's sing of love.
あとさ夜明けまで 君の声が聞きたい Oh Yeah
And also, until dawn, I want to hear your voice, Oh Yeah.
愛いつも変わり映えしなくてさ
Love always stays the same...
僕ら同じことで悩んだり 悲しんだり 笑ったりしてるのにな
Even though we worry, grieve, and laugh about the same things.
分かり合うのはそう簡単じゃない
Understanding each other isn't that easy.
ただこんなにも君とリンクしてる 重なっていく
But I'm linking with you this much, overlapping.
今 I Love You で始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれよ
Now, shine more light on us who start with 'I Love You'.
変わらない愛や希望の類も まだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in things like unchanging love and hope.
ほら I Miss You で諦めモードでも OK 飛ばしていけよ
Look, even if it's 'I Miss You' and resignation mode, it's OK, keep going.
時代が食らい未来が待ち受けど 愛を歌おう
Though the times are harsh and the future awaits, let's sing of love.
僕が生まれる前よりも ずっと昔から続くように そういつも傷つけ合ってまた 愛し合うのさ
As if continuing from long before I was born, hurting each other and loving each other again.
センキュー！いかーん。
Thank you! Oh no...
歌詞間違えた！すみませんでした！
I messed up the lyrics! I'm so sorry!
うわぁ、やっちまったやっちまった、大変だ大変だ大変だ。
Waaah, I blew it, I blew it. This is bad, this is bad...
大変だ、やっちゃったよ、おいおいおい。
It's bad, I did it. Hey, hey, hey.
すみませんでした、でも最高に楽しい！
I'm sorry, but this is so much fun!
バレへんバレへん、あーって途中で思ったけど、
They won't notice, they won't notice. I thought 'Ah!' in the middle,
ちょっとあの、ごまかしてみました。
But I, uh, tried to play it off.
すみませんでした本当に、申し訳ない。
I'm really sorry, my apologies.
次の曲、まだあるので。
There's still the next song.
ちょっとその前に、水とか飲んでもいいかな？
Before that, can I drink some water?
もーらお、飲んでもいいかな、いい？
I'll take some. Can I drink? Is it okay?
あぁー。
Ahhh.
うまっ！
Good!
水がうめんじゃ、生命の源なんじゃ。
The water is so good. It's the source of life.
ありがとね。いや、やっぱ緊張するね。
Thank you. Man, I really am nervous.
では、早く告知も聞きたいと思うので、
Now, I'm sure you want to hear the announcement soon,
次の曲、行ってもいいですか！？
So, can we go to the next song!?
行ってもいいですか！？
Can we go!?
準備はいいですか！？
Are you ready!?
OK!
では...
Then...
いきましょう！
Let's go!
ヴィラン。
Villain.
ヴィラン
作詞・作曲：てにをは
Villain
Lyrics & Composition: teniwoha
きっと手を繋ぐだけで　ゾッとされる
Surely just holding hands, you'll be shuddered at
ラットレース一抜けたら　通報される
If you get out of the rat race first, you'll be reported
ミュータントじゃない　ただの僕さ
I'm not a mutant, I'm just me
XとかYとか
X and Y and such
べき論者様は　善悪多罪
The 'should-be' theorists are full of good, evil, and many sins
僕が君を侵害するって　言いふらしてる
They're spreading rumors that I'm infringing on you
Oh Mr. Crazy Villain Villain
蛇蝎の如く花弁
Petals like a snake-scorpion
違う服着て　君の前では男子の振りする
Wearing different clothes, I pretend to be a boy in front of you
拝啓　Dr. Durr-ra-Durr-ra
迎えに来てください
Dear Dr. Durr-ra-Durr-ra
Please come and pick me up
誰も知らない　誰かにとって僕はもうヴィラン
To someone who knows nothing, I'm already a villain
蛇蝎が辛い　蛇蝎が辛い
The snake-scorpion is hard, the snake-scorpion is hard
挙げ句の果ての　ヴィラン
At the end of it all, a villain
逸脱の性がまた　ひた隠す
The nature of deviation is hidden once more
雄蕊と雄蕊じゃ　立ち行かないの
With stamen and stamen, it won't work out
ねぇ　知ってんの？
カランボルトにパッチにポッチ
Hey, did you know?
A bolt, a patch, and a nub
造花も果ては　実を結ぶ
Artificial flowers will eventually bear fruit
腐ってんじゃねぇよ　多種多様の性
Don't be rotten, diverse genders
悲しい悲しい　話をしようか　ゼラチン質の
Shall we tell a sad, sad story? A gelatinous one
Oh Mr. Crazy Villain Villain
可能性に幸あれ
Happiness to the possibilities
僕のハートは1LDK　独り占めさせてよ
My heart is a 1LDK, let me have it all to myself
はい　ずっと　ヨロ・ヨロ
微熱抱いていいのに
Yes, always staggering
It's okay to hold onto a slight fever
誰も知らない　知られたくない　皮膚の下
Nobody knows, I don't want anyone to know, under the skin
素晴らしき役を　共に捧げる歌
A song dedicated together to the wonderful role
骨までしゃぶり尽くしてやりゃ　阿修羅に
If you suck it dry to the bone, you'll become an Ashura
残酷な町ほど　綺麗に日が沈む
The sun sets more beautifully in the cruelest towns
我儘勝手に　踊る操り人形（ポップ）みたいな
Selfishly dancing like a marionette
みんな行くぞー！
Everyone, let's go!
Oh!
Oh Mr. Crazy Villain Villain
蛇蝎の如く花弁
Petals like a snake-scorpion
違う服着て　君の前では男子の振りする
Wearing different clothes, I pretend to be a boy in front of you
拝啓　Dr. Durr-ra-Durr-ra
ここだよ
Dear Dr. Durr-ra-Durr-ra
I'm right here
誰も知らない　誰かにとって僕はもうヴィラン
To someone who knows nothing, I'm already a villain
蛇蝎が辛い　蛇蝎が辛い
The snake-scorpion is hard, the snake-scorpion is hard
挙げ句の果ての　ヴィラン
At the end of it all, a villain
イェーイ！
Yay!
Thank you!
聴いてくれて本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for listening!
いや、やっぱり歌は難しい、本当に難しいけど、楽しい！
Man, as expected, singing is hard, it's really hard, but it's fun!
特にみんなにこうやって聴いてもらって、
Especially having everyone listen like this,
同じ時間を共有してもらえることが本当に、
本当にかげがえのない時間だなぁと思います。
and sharing the same time, I think it's truly,
truly an irreplaceable time.
では、ここでアレいきましょうかね。
Well, let's go with *that* now.
まず告知１！
First, announcement 1!
なんと角巻わためのお誕生日記念の...
Believe it or not, for Tsunomaki Watame's birthday celebration...
グッズが、で、で、で、で、で、で、でま...
The goods, are, are, are, are, are, are, are...
でます！
Are coming out!
角巻わため 誕生日記念2021
6月6日 販売開始
Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2021
Sales start June 6th
わー！バッチリタイミング！
スタッフさんありがとうございます！
Wow! Perfect timing!
Thank you, staff!
角巻わため、誕生日記念2021！
Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2021!
記念ボイス、全種セット、えーと4種類ありまして、
Memorial voice, full set, uh, there are 4 types,
なんと全部自分で、あの物語というか、あれを...
And believe it or not, I [wrote] the whole story, or rather, the...
…を考えて。ポチ。そして…
...please consider it. *Click*. And...
記念グッズ二種。
Two types of commemorative goods.
これは個別の画像があったりしますかな？
I wonder if there are individual images for these?
ぷるり！
Pruri!
なんと！え、ふーみママ描き下ろし、あったかブランケット〜！
Look at this! A warm blanket illustrated by Fuumi-mama!
ぷるり！
Pruri!
たぶんこれでね、あのー、ま、今日買っていただいて、え、届くまでにちょっと時間がかかると思うんですよ。
With this, if you buy it today, it'll probably take a while for it to reach you.
たぶんこう涼しくなった頃にこのブランケットがね、届くんじゃないかなという
It'll probably arrive right when it's getting cooler...
想定でブランケット、今回作らせていただきました。
...so we made this blanket with that in mind.
そして…
And...
ぷるり！
Pruri!
ぷるりの音が面白くて笑ってしまうけど、これ、これこれこれ！これ目玉商品ですよ、これ！
That 'pruri' sound is so funny I can't stop laughing, but look at this! This is the featured item!
これ！原田たけひと先生描き下ろし、わためぇNight Fever!! 温感マグカップ！
This! The 'Watame Night Fever!! Temperature-sensitive Mug' illustrated by Harada Takehito-sensei!
これ、知ってる？原田たけひと先生って、みんな知ってますか？
Do you know him? Does everyone know Harada Takehito-sensei?
あの、わための大好きな日本一ソフトウェアさんの、あの、あれわかるでしょ？
He's from Nippon Ichi Software, who I love, you know the one, right?
わためも声とかやらせてもらった、ディスガイア！
Disgaea, the game I even did voice work for!
そう、ディスガイアのね、あのイラストを担当されてる方なんですよ。そう！
Yes, he's the person in charge of the illustrations for Disgaea. That's right!
なんと今回引き受けていただきまして、書いていただくことができました！イエーイ！
He actually agreed to do it this time, and was able to draw this for us! Yay!
イエーイ！しかも、え、9時50分。もうね、たぶん、あのブースのページはね、オープンしてると思うので。
Yay! Also, it's 9:50 PM. I think the Booth page should be open by now.
え、販売は10時からになるんですけど、よかったらそっちもチェックしてみてください。
Sales start at 10 PM, so please check it out if you'd like.
で、これが、あの冷たい状態だと、わためがね、暗闇でこうぽつんと…
And when it's cold, Watame is just sitting there in the dark...
ぽつんと一人でフィーバーしてるんだけど、あの温かい飲み物をね、入れてもらいますと、なんと！
Having a fever all by herself, but when you pour in a hot drink, look!
ステージと、あとわためいとと、ライトとかがね、ぱぁっと浮かび上がってきて、
The stage, the Watamates, and the lights all suddenly appear,
華やかなステージをみんなで一緒に作り上げるっていう、そういう、あの…
creating a vibrant stage together with everyone...
ま、ライブとかしたいねっていう、夢、夢？希望？も込めて、このマグカップ作らせていただきました。
I made this mug with the dream... dream? Hope? of wanting to do a concert.
あとはね、特典もありまして。
There's also a bonus.
ぷるり！ぷるりない。
Pruri! No 'pruri'.
これは、このボイス四種類セットと、グッズ二種類セット、ま、全部セットですね、買っていただいた方に、
For those who buy the 4-voice set and the 2-goods set, the full set...
ふーみママ描き下ろしイラストポストカード。あのブランケットのとはちょっと表情がね、違うんですけど。
You get an illustrated postcard by Fuumi-mama. Her expression is a bit different from the one on the blanket.
これになんと、え、わため直筆サインもいたします！
And I'll even be hand-signing these!
しかも、え、数量限定… しません！全部書きます！
And they are limited... NOT! I'll sign them all!
なので、争いは起きないと思うので、ちょっと10時からの販売ね、
So I don't think there will be any fighting. For the 10 PM sale,
そんな焦らないで、戦争しないでね。
please don't rush or start a war.
はい、数量限定しません。いや、もしとんでもないぐらい来たら、
Yes, no limited quantities. Well, if an overwhelming number come in,
ちょっとこれ以上はって運営さんストップがかかるかもしれないけど、
the staff might tell me to stop, but...
一応今のところ制限なしです。
For now, there's no limit.
そしてあと特典ボイスもついてきてます。これが、え、まとめて一万円かな？全部セットで一万円となっております。
And it also comes with a bonus voice. All together it's 10,000 yen, I think? The full set is 10,000 yen.
あとね、個別販売も今回ありまして、あのマグカップだけもう一個欲しいなとか、ブランケットだけもう一個欲しいなとか、そういった方は単品で買っていただくこともできます。
Also, they are available individually this time, so if you want an extra mug or blanket, you can buy them separately.
あ、腱鞘炎、気をつける！
Oh, I'll be careful of tendonitis!
たぶんね、一日、こう何枚ずつとかでやっていけば大丈夫だと思うんだよね。
I think if I do a certain number of sheets a day, it'll be fine.
そう、なんで一万円となっております。よかったら、このあと10時から、買ってください！お願いします！
So it's 10,000 yen. Please check it out and buy it from 10 PM! Please!
お願いします！丹精込めたグッズです、お願いします！
Please! These are goods I put my heart and soul into, so please!
そして、え、このあと告知に、10時15分から、これもう枠立ってるんですけど、え、プレミア公開の動画が…
And next is an announcement, at 10:15 PM, the stream is already set up, a premiere video...
「怪物」！歌ってみた！
'Monster'! A cover song!
ぶわぁ〜！べぁ〜！
Bwaa! Beaa!
SE！ぶわぁ〜！怪物の歌ってみた！
SE! Bwaa! The 'Monster' cover!
あ、これは...
Ah, this is...
うぇーい、ぱほぱほ！
Yay, paho paho!
お世話になってるみんなへ
To everyone who has been supporting me,
わためからのプレゼントに
as a present from Watame...
なるかわからないけどプレゼントです。ははは！
I don't know if it'll be a good one, but here's a present. Hahaha!
22時15分から『怪物』歌ってみた上がりますので
My cover of 'Kaibutsu' will be uploaded at 22:15,
そっちも、はい、配信のあと、ま、グッズを買ってもらって
so after the stream, please buy some merch,
そのあと『怪物』を見てもらって、リレーしていただけたらなと思います
then watch 'Kaibutsu'. I hope you can do a relay like that.
あと、えー、6月、もう一個歌ってみた動画を上げます
Also, in June, I'll upload another cover song video.
そして、6月、7月、オリ曲も投稿予定がありますので
And in June and July, I'm planning to post original songs too,
楽しみに待っててくれよな！
so please look forward to them!
そしてそして、え、最後にこの『怪物』のイラストですね
And finally, for the illustration for 'Kaibutsu',
描いていただいた壁紙を、この後わためのYouTubeコミュニティのところに
the wallpaper that was drawn, I'll post it on my YouTube community page later
ダウンロードURLとパスワードをね、ちょっと記載して公開させていただきますので
along with the download URL and password.
一般公開、全員ダウンロードできるようになっております！
It'll be public so everyone can download it!
ははは！
Hahaha!
『怪物』のイラストのダウンロードもよかったら壁紙に使用してね
Please download the 'Kaibutsu' illustration and use it as your wallpaper if you'd like.
盛りだくさんでしょ？
It's a lot, isn't it?
ま、こんな感じ。グッズと、えー、歌ってみたと、
So, we have merch, the cover song,
ま、今後歌ってみたもう一個上がる予定のと、オリ曲も上がる予定のと、
the other cover song coming soon, the original songs coming soon,
壁紙ダウンロードこの後できるよ。ははは！
and the wallpaper download available later. Hahaha!
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
わぁー、今日はめっちゃ楽しかったなぁ
Wow, today was so much fun.
あっという間だった1時間が。みんな本当にありがとう
The hour just flew by. Thank you so much, everyone.
でも、まだ足りないよな？
But it's not enough yet, right?
みんなの愛を最後にもう一回もらってもいいですか？
Can I have your love one more time at the end?
ラストの曲でみんなの愛をたくさんもらってもいいですかー！？
Can I receive lots of your love with the last song!?
じゃあ、本当にラストです
Okay, this is really the last one.
創聖のアクエリオン
Genesis of Aquarion
作詞：岩里 祐穂、河森 正治 / 作曲：菅野 よう子
Sousei no Aquarion
Lyrics: Yuho Iwasato, Shoji Kawamori / Composition: Yoko Kanno
世界の始まりの日 命の樹の下で
On the day the world began, beneath the Tree of Life
クジラたちの声の 遠い残響 二人で聞いた
We heard the distant echoes of the whales' voices together
失くしたものすべて 愛したものすべて
Everything we lost, everything we loved
この手に抱きしめて 今はどこを 彷徨い行くの
I hold them in these hands. Where are they wandering now?
答えの潜む 琥珀の太陽
The amber sun where the answer hides
出会わなければ 殺戮の天使でいられた
If we hadn't met, I could have remained an angel of slaughter
光る瞬き 持つ魂
The soul with the shining twinkle
傷つかないで 僕の羽 この気持ち知るため生まれてきた
Don't get hurt, my wings. I was born to know this feeling
一万年と二千年前から愛してる
I've loved you since twelve thousand years ago
八千年過ぎた頃からもっと恋しくなった
My love grew even stronger eight thousand years ago
一億と二千年あとも愛してる
I'll still love you one hundred million and two thousand years from now
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I knew you, the music in my hell has never ceased
愛してるぜー！
I love you guys!
世界が終わる前に 命が終わる前に
Before the world ends, before life ends
眠る嘆き 払っておいて 君の香り 抱きしめたいよ
Let me brush away the sleeping grief. I want to hold your scent
耳澄ませた 罪の記憶
I listened closely to the memories of sin
宿命に飲まれ 立ち尽くす 麗しき月
Swallowed by fate, the beautiful moon stands still
蘇れ 永久に枯れぬ光
Be reborn, the light that never withers for eternity
汚されないで 君の夢 祈り宿しながら生まれてきた
Don't let your dreams be tainted. I was born while carrying prayers
一万年と二千年前から愛してる
I've loved you since twelve thousand years ago
コメント足りないよ！
More comments!
八千年過ぎた頃からもっと恋しくなった
My love grew even stronger eight thousand years ago
一億と二千年あとも愛してる
I'll still love you one hundred million and two thousand years from now
ナイス！
Nice!
君を知ったその日から 僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Since the day I knew you, the music in my hell has never ceased
僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
...music never ceases in my hell.
君が繰り返し大人になって
As you repeatedly become an adult
何度も何度も遠くへ行って
And go far away again and again,
見守る僕が 眠れない僕が
I watch over you, I who cannot sleep,
くしゃくしゃになったとしても
Even if I become a crumpled mess.
君の名を歌うために
In order to sing your name,
一万年と二千年前から愛してる
I've loved you since twelve thousand years ago.
八千年以上過ぎた頃からもっと恋しくなった
Since eight thousand years passed, I've loved you even more.
一億と二千年後も愛してる
I'll love you even one hundred million and two thousand years from now.
君を知ったその日から
From the day I first knew you,
一万年と二千年前から
From twelve thousand years ago...
もっともっと！
More, more!
八千年以上過ぎた頃からもっと恋しくなった
Since eight thousand years passed, I've loved you even more.
一億と二千年後も愛してる！
I'll love you even one hundred million and two thousand years from now!
君を知ったその日から
From the day I first knew you,
僕の地獄に音楽は絶えない
Music never ceases in my hell.
今宵のわためも
Tonight's Watame, too,
ドドドド突っ走りますのでよろしくお願いします
Will keep on going full speed ahead, so please support me!
今日は本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for today!